Alexander R. Pereyra

18806 NW 1st Street, Pembroke Pines, FL 33029 | H: (954) 608-7897 | E: alexpereyra@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://alexander.pereyra.info

Objective

Highly motivated IT Engineer with ten years of experience seeking to leverage technical and professional expertise as a Cloud Engineer. Focused and determined to learn, innovate, and contribute in meaningful ways to support continuous growth and success.

Certifications

AWS Certified SysOps Administrator - Associate
AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate
AWS Certified Developer - Associate
Certification Transcript
(19) AWS training certifications
(22+) A Cloud Guru training courses completed

Professional Experience

SENIOR CLOUD ENGINEER | 02/2019 to Current

CloudHesive - Fort Lauderdale, FL

- Design, implement, and release of cloud solutions for major clients.
- Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using GitHub, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, CodeDeploy, Jenkins, ECS, S3, ELB, Route53.
- Build and deploy Docker containers to break up monolithic applications into microservices, improving developer workflow, increasing scalability, and optimizing speed. Using all best practices and patterns in many development scenarios such as lift and shift, rearchitect, and rewrite.
- Build custom tools and CLI wrappers in python/powershell to more efficiently manage cloud infrastructure, perform maintenance, and monitor infrastructure.
- Automation of AWS account builds along with baseline resources.
- Enforce and promote practice of versioning, immutable infrastructure, declarative DevOps.
- Implement automation for policy and standards using AWS Service Catalog, AWS Config with Slack integration. Use of Parameter Store, Secrets Manager, Systems Manager features.
- AWS cost control reducing resource sprawl using tagging tools, resource cycling tools, and cost analysis tools to identify resources, measure usage, design for cost.
- Actively manage, improve, and monitor cloud infrastructure on AWS using Datadog, Sumologic, CloudWatch, ELK stack, custom pipeline visualization, ect.
- Design using DevSecOps strategies to meet HIPAA security and compliance standards that conform with fedramp, soc, ect. audits. This includes identifying, planning, and architecting solutions using appropriate AWS services to securely process, store, and transmit data based in business needs.
- Assessment of existing customer environments of operational status, architecture (PAAS, IAAS, FAAS, SAAS), deployment models, data flow, security and compliance needs.
- Use of AWS inspector, Chef in-spec for security state of instances, AMIs, network, ect. Ansible/Puppet for deployment of CIS OS hardening.
- Deploy and maintain AWS account security standards using CloudFormation/Lambda. Services defined/deployed across accounts/regions include GuardDuty, AWS Config (this included account level benchmarks for all AWS resources), ect.

CLOUD ENGINEER | 10/2018 to 02/2019

Royal Caribbean Cruises - Miramar, FL

- Integrated Directory service solution, implementated of Amazon workspaces, and identified solutions for centralized account management.
- Automation for security team. Created and implemented scripts that built terraform templates to dynamically change/append security group rules.
- Developed aws cli wrapper for developers to assume roles for cross account access leveraging ADFS saml authentication.
- Snapshot management automated using python/shell scripts.

IT CITRIX ENGINEER | 05/2014 to 10/2018

Royal Caribbean Cruises - Miramar, FL

- Managed, supported, and implemented infrastructure with 85+ hosts, 675+ VMs, and 2200+ concurrent user sessions within Hybrid Cloud environment serving desktops and 150+ applications for 7 major Contact Call Centers globally
- Executed major migrations of infrastructure to Cloud/Citrix XenDesktop 7.15 from XenApp 6.5 including analysis of business needs and application/desktop infrastructure build requirements
- Provided end-to-end operational support of global environment using VMware VC & ESXi hypervisors, HP/Cisco UCS, Microsoft Windows Server
- Owned projects introducing new applications/services including: configuration of server blade, VM buildout based on requirements, migration from dev/test/production, configuration & testing of application/service, monitoring resources.
- Provided technical resolution to incident/problem events related to Citrix/Windows server infrastructure
- · Planned and implemented capacity planning and infrastructure enhancement of application delivery solutions
- Involved in change and risk management in evaluating impact of infrastructure changes

IT ANALYST - CONFIGURATION CENTER | 04/2010 to 05/2014

Royal Caribbean Cruises - Weston, FL

- Diagnosed and resolved all IT hardware issues across 32+ fleet of ships internationally
- Significantly helped reduce cost for out-of-warranty hardware through in-house repairs (laptops, workstations, and servers)
- Helped reduce time and cost for hardware orders through streamlining logistics with 3rd party vendors

Projects

- Automated build and deployment of Windows ADFS server(s) with custom cert import, domain join, decoupled database, AD integration, using S3, CloudFormation, and Powershell. (See my portfolio for details).
- Designed, implemented, and deployed automated deployment solutions (for hybrid on-prem as well) using github and CodeBuild for several major clients.
- Build, implement, and maintain automated hardened AMI pipeline using CodeBuild, packer, and Ansible. (See my portfolio for details. Puppet solution available as well.)
- Lift and shift / refactor of monolithic application in python, java (groovy), gradle, stash artifactory updated from a developer laptop into an automated Jenkins pipeline leveraging docker, ECS, ECR, GitHub. New code development for parameter store, secrets manager, directory and file manipulation in python for application configuration. (See my portfolio for details).
- Automated build of AWS workspaces for POC including VPC, Directory service, and workspaces in a well architected manner using Service Catalog, CloudFormation, Python. (See my portfolio for details).
- Development of custom cli wrappers for management of AWS resources and automated solutions. (See my portfolio for detailed example of solutions).
- Deployment and maintenance of automated AMI build pipeline for OS hardening (linux distributions) to meet CIS benchmark security standards. This solution leveraged github (or CodeCommit), Packer, Ansible, AWS CodeBuild.
- Implemented encryption in-transit/at rest application data requirements by building ssl communication on load balancer (AWS ACM for CA/Cert import) leveraging AWS KMS. In addition, used python cryptography, hiera-eyaml, certificate authority packages to satisfy security standards.

Hobbies

Piano Weight training

Education

Florida Atlantic University - Boca Raton, FL | Bachelor of Arts Bachelors of General Studies (B.G.S.), 2014

Organizations

President | 02/2012 to 12/2014 Devonaire Homeowners Association - Pembroke Pines, FL

References

Jack McElwayne - Senior Solutions Engineer at VMware Luis Suarez - Cloud Principle Engineer Jay Vega - Cloud Infrastructure Engineer at Royal Caribbean Cruises